{
    "collection": [
    {
        "section": "Abstract Reasoning",
        "subsection": "Number and letter series",
        "questions": [
          {
            "id": 1,
            "question": "Look at this series: 2, 1, (1/2), (1/4), ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["(1/3)", "(1/8)", "(2/8)", "(1/16)"],
            "answer": "(1/8)",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 2,
            "question": "Look at this series: 7, 10, 8, 11, 9, 12, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["7", "10", "12", "13"],
            "answer": "10",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 3,
            "question": "Look at this series: 36, 34, 30, 28, 24, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["20", "22", "23", "26"],
            "answer": "22",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 4,
            "question": "Look at this series: 22, 21, 23, 22, 24, 23, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["22", "24", "25", "26"],
            "answer": "25",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 5,
            "question": "Look at this series: 53, 53, 40, 40, 27, 27, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["12", "14", "27", "53"],
            "answer": "1",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 6,
            "question": "Look at this series: 21, 9, 21, 11, 21, 13, 21, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["14", "15", "21", "23"],
            "answer": "15",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 7,
            "question": "Look at this series: 58, 52, 46, 40, 34, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["26", "28", "30", "32"],
            "answer": "28",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 8,
            "question": "Look at this series: 3, 4, 7, 8, 11, 12, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["7", "10", "14", "15"],
            "answer": "15",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 9,
            "question": "Look at this series: 8, 22, 8, 28, 8, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["9", "29", "32", "34"],
            "answer": "34",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 10,
            "question": "Look at this series: 31, 29, 24, 22, 17, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["15", "14", "13", "12"],
            "answer": "15",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 11,
            "question": "Look at this series: 1.5, 2.3, 3.1, 3.9, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["4.2", "4.4", "4.7", "5.1"],
            "answer": "4.7",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 12,
            "question": "Look at this series: 14, 28, 20, 40, 32, 64, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["52", "56", "96", "128"],
            "answer": "56",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 13,
            "question": "Look at this series: 2, 4, 6, 8, 10, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["11", "12", "13", "14"],
            "answer": "12",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 14,
            "question": "Look at this series: 201, 202, 204, 207, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["205", "208", "210", "211"],
            "answer": "211",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 15,
            "question": "Look at this series: 544, 509, 474, 439, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["404", "414", "420", "445"],
            "answer": "404",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 16,
            "question": "Look at this series: 80, 10, 70, 15, 60, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["20", "25", "30", "50"],
            "answer": "20",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 17,
            "question": "Look at this series: 2, 6, 18, 54, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["108", "148", "162", "216"],
            "answer": "162",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 18,
            "question": "Look at this series: 5.2, 4.8, 4.4, 4, ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["3", "3.3", "3.5", "3.6"],
            "answer": "3.6",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 19,
            "question": "Look at this series: 8, 6, 9, 23, 87 , ... What number should come next?",
            "options": ["128", "226", "324", "429"],
            "answer": "429",
            "s_id": 1
          },
          {
            "id": 20,
            "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
            "options": ["11 5", "11 8", "5 10", "10 5"],
            "answer": "11 5",
            "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 21,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["25 18", "25 29", "24 21", "22 26"],
                "answer": "25 29",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 22,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["59 66", "56 62", "58 66", "54 61"],
                "answer": "54 61",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 23,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["2 46", "44 50", "42 48", "40 42"],
                "answer": "42 28",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 24,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["19 33", "33 35", "15 33", "19 21"],
                "answer": "19 33",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 25,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["9 10", "10 4", "9 4", "8 9"],
                "answer": "8 9",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 26,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["26 23", "34 20", "27 28", "23 28"],
                "answer": "23 28",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 27,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["2 18", "4 12", "2 14", "14 14"],
                "answer": "2 14",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 28,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["41 44", "37 18", "37 41", "38 41"],
                "answer": "37 41",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 29,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["25 15", "25 85", "85 35", "25 75"],
                "answer": "25 85",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 30,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["47 52", "46 52", "45 49", "46 51"],
                "answer": "46 51",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 31,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["39 44", "38 44", "38 43", "33 38"],
                "answer": "38 43",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 32,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["44 34", "42 36", "40 34", "38 32"],
                "answer": "42 36",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 33,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["8 8", "11 14", "8 9", "11 8"],
                "answer": "11 8",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 34,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["29 61", "27 20", "31 61", "29 22"],
                "answer": "29 22",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 35,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["14 13", "18 21", "12 13", "18 17"],
                "answer": "18 17",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 36,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["28 32", "28 22", "22 28", "22 26"],
                "answer": "22 28",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 37,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["13 4", "13 5", "9 4", "4 4"],
                "answer": "13 4",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 38,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["26 40", "29 36", "40 25", "40 50"],
                "answer": "40 25",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 39,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["70 65", "60 70", "60 65", "65 70"],
                "answer": "65 70",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 40,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["25 22", "26 23", "26 24", "25 23"],
                "answer": "26 24",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 41,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["36 40", "33 37", "38 42", "34 38"],
                "answer": "34 28",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 42,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["15 12", "8 15", "15 19", "8 5"],
                "answer": "15 12",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 43,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["10 5", "13 8", "12 7", "10 8"],
                "answer": "10 8",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 44,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["22 35", "35 19", "19 35", "19 24"],
                "answer": "19 35",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 45,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["21 23", "20 21", "20 17", "25 27"],
                "answer": "20 21",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 46,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["50 62", "50 72", "62 62", "62 80"],
                "answer": "50 62",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 47,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["24 21", "22 19", "29 32", "23 20"],
                "answer": "23 20",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 48,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["8 16", "16 16", "12 12", "12 16"],
                "answer": "12 12",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 49,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["15 11", "15 13", "11 15", "15 17"],
                "answer": "11 15",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 50,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["35 33", "32 36", "36 36", "33 34"],
                "answer": "36 36",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            
            {
                "id": 51,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["26 28", "29 34", "29 31", "26 31"],
                "answer": "29 31",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 52,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["14 4", "14 17", "19 13", "19 14"],
                "answer": "19 14",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 53,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["11 8", "12 8", "11 7", "32 29"],
                "answer": "11 8",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 54,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["80 66", "64 82", "66 80", "66 82"],
                "answer": "66 80",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 55,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["10 12", "35 32", "35 10", "10 52"],
                "answer": "35 10",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 56,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["25 25", "20 22", "23 25", "27 32"],
                "answer": "23 25",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 57,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["8 5", "8 2", "5 5", "5 8"],
                "answer": "5 5",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 58,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["25 18", "30 13", "18 20", "25 22"],
                "answer": "25 18",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 59,
                "question": "Look carefully for the pattern, and then choose which pair of numbers comes next.",
                "options": ["23 23", "23 26", "21 24", "24 24"],
                "answer": "23 23",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 60,
                "question": "Look at this series: F2, __, D8, C16, B32, ... What number should fill the blank?",
                "options": ["A16", "G4", "E4", "E3"],
                "answer": "E4",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 61,
                "question": "Look at this series: 664, 332, 340, 170, ____, 89, ... What number should fill the blank?",
                "options": ["85", "97", "109", "178"],
                "answer": "178",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 62,
                "question": "Look at this series: V, VIII, XI, XIV, __, XX, ... What number should fill the blank?",
                "options": ["IX", "XXIII", "XV", "XVII"],
                "answer": "XVII",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 63,
                "question": "Look at this series: 70, 71, 76, __, 81, 86, 70, 91, ... What number should fill the blank?",
                "options": ["70", "71", "80", "96"],
                "answer": "70",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 64,
                "question": "Look at this series: 8, 43, 11, 41, __, 39, 17, ... What number should fill in the blank?",
                "options": ["8", "14", "43", "44"],
                "answer": "14",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 65,
                "question": "Look at this series: VI, 10, V, 11, __, 12, III, ... What number should fill the blank?",
                "options": ["II", "IV", "IX", "14"],
                "answer": "IV",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 66,
                "question": "Look at this series: (1/9), (1/3), 1, ____ , 9, ... What number should fill the blank?",
                "options": ["(2/3)", "3", "6", "27"],
                "answer": "3",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 67,
                "question": "Look at this series: 83, 73, 93, 63, __, 93, 43, ... What number should fill the blank?",
                "options": ["33", "53", "73", "93"],
                "answer": "53",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 68,
                "question": "Look at this series: 15, __, 27, 27, 39, 39, ... What number should fill the blank?",
                "options": ["51", "39", "23", "15"],
                "answer": "15",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 69,
                "question": "Look at this series: 72, 76, 73, 77, 74, __, 75, ... What number should fill the blank?",
                "options": ["70", "71", "75", "78"],
                "answer": "78",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 70,
                "question": "Look at this series: J14, L16, __, P20, R22, ... What number should fill the blank?",
                "options": ["S24", "N18", "M18", "T24"],
                "answer": "N18",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 71,
                "question": "Look at this series: 4, 7, 25, 10, __, 20, 16, 19, ... What number should fill the blank?",
                "options": ["13", "15", "20", "28"],
                "answer": "13",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 72,
                "question": "Look at this series: XXIV, XX, __, XII, VIII, ... What number should fill the blank?",
                "options": ["XXII", "XIII", "XVI", "IV"],
                "answer": "XVI",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 73,
                "question": "Look at this series: 0.15, 0.3, ____, 1.2, 2.4, ... What number should fill the blank?",
                "options": ["4.8", "0.006", "0.6", "0.9"],
                "answer": "0.6",
                "s_id": "1"
            },
            {
                "id": 74,
                "question": "Look at this series: U32, V29, __, X23, Y20, ... What number should fill the blank?",
                "options": ["W26", "W17", "Z17", "Z26"],
                "answer": "W26",
                "s_id": "1"
            }        
        ]
    },
    
    

    {
        "section": "Abstract Reasoning",
        "subsection": "Odd Man Out",
        "questions": [
        {
            "id": 1,
            "question": "Find the odd man out. 3, 5, 11, 14, 17, 21",
            "options": ["21", "17", "14", "3"],
            "answer": "14",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 2,
            "question": "Find the odd man out. 8, 27, 64, 100, 125, 216, 343",
            "options": ["27", "100", "125", "343"],
            "answer": "100",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 3,
            "question": "Find the odd man out. 10, 25, 45, 54, 60, 75, 80",
            "options": ["10", "45", "54", "75"],
            "answer": "54",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 4,
            "question": "Find the odd man out. 396, 462, 572, 427, 671, 264",
            "options": ["396", "427", "671", "264"],
            "answer": "427",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 5,
            "question": "Find the odd man out. 6, 9, 15, 21, 24, 28, 30",
            "options": ["28", "21", "24", "30"],
            "answer": "28",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 6,
            "question": "Find the odd man out. 1, 4, 9, 16, 23, 25, 36",
            "options": ["9", "23", "25", "36"],
            "answer": "23",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 7,
            "question": "Find the odd man out. 1, 4, 9, 16, 20, 36, 49",
            "options": ["1", "9", "20", "49"],
            "answer": "20",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 8,
            "question": "Find the odd man out. 2, 5, 10, 17, 26, 37, 50, 64",
            "options": ["50", "26", "37", "64"],
            "answer": "64",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 9,
            "question": "Find the odd man out. 10, 14, 16, 18, 21, 24, 26",
            "options": ["26", "24", "21", "18"],
            "answer": "21",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 10,
            "question": "Find the odd man out. 16, 25, 36, 72, 144, 196, 225",
            "options": ["36", "72", "196", "225"],
            "answer": "72",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 11,
            "question": "Find the odd man out. 331, 482, 551, 263, 383, 362, 284",
            "options": ["263", "383", "331", "551"],
            "answer": "383",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 12,
            "question": "Find the odd man out. 835, 734, 642, 751, 853, 981, 532",
            "options": ["751", "853", "981", "532"],
            "answer": "751",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 13,
            "question": "Find the odd man out. 41, 43, 47, 53, 61, 71, 73, 81",
            "options": ["61", "71", "73", "81"],
            "answer": "81",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 14,
            "question": "Find the odd man out. 3, 5, 7, 12, 17, 19",
            "options": ["19", "17", "5", "12"],
            "answer": "12",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 15,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the given sequence of numbers. 582, 605, 588, 611, 634, 617, 600",
            "options": ["634", "611", "605", "600"],
            "answer": "634",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 16,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the given sequence of numbers. 22, 33, 66, 99, 121, 279, 594",
            "options": ["33", "121", "279", "594"],
            "answer": "278",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 17,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the given sequence of numbers. 8, 13, 21, 32, 47, 63, 83",
            "options": ["47", "63", "32", "83"],
            "answer": "47",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 18,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the given sequence of numbers. 1, 8, 27, 64, 124, 216, 343",
            "options": ["8", "27", "64", "124"],
            "answer": "124",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 19,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the given sequence of numbers. 1, 2, 6, 15, 31, 56, 91",
            "options": ["31", "91", "56", "15"],
            "answer": "91",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 20,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the given sequence of numbers. 52, 51, 48, 43, 34, 27, 16",
            "options": ["27", "34", "43", "48"],
            "answer": "34",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 21,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the given sequence of numbers. 4, 6, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12",
            "options": ["10", "11", "12", "9"],
            "answer": "11",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 22,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the given sequence of numbers. 105, 85, 60, 30, 0, -45, -90",
            "options": ["0", "85", "-45", "60"],
            "answer": "0",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 23,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the given sequence of numbers. 5, 16, 6, 16, 7, 16, 9",
            "options": ["9", "7", "6", "None of these"],
            "answer": "9",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 24,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the given sequence of numbers. 125, 127, 130, 135, 142, 153, 165",
            "options": ["130", "142", "153", "165"],
            "answer": "165",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 25,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the given sequence of numbers. 46080, 3840, 384, 48, 24, 2, 1",
            "options": ["1", "2", "24", "384"],
            "answer": "24",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 26,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the given sequence of numbers. 6, 13, 18, 25, 30, 37, 40",
            "options": ["25", "30", "37", "40"],
            "answer": "40",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 27,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the given sequence of numbers. 36, 54, 18, 27, 9, 18.5, 4.5",
            "options": ["4.5", "18.5", "54", "18"],
            "answer": "18.5",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 28,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the given sequence of numbers. 56, 72, 90, 110, 132, 150",
            "options": ["72", "110", "132", "150"],
            "answer": "150",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 29,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the given sequence of numbers. 25, 36, 49, 81, 121, 169, 225",
            "options": ["36", "49", "121", "169"],
            "answer": "36",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 30,
            "question": "Insert the missing number. 16, 33, 65, 131, 261, (....)",
            "options": ["523", "521", "613", "721"],
            "answer": "523",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 31,
            "question": "Insert the missing number. 10, 5, 13, 10, 16, 20, 19, (....)",
            "options": ["22", "40", "38", "23"],
            "answer": "40",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 32,
            "question": "Insert the missing number. 1, 4, 9, 16, 25, 36, 49, (....)",
            "options": ["54", "56", "64", "81"],
            "answer": "64",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 33,
            "question": "Insert the missing number. 2, 4, 12, 48, 240, (....)",
            "options": ["960", "1280", "1200", "2400"],
            "answer": "960",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 34,
            "question": "Insert the missing number. 8, 7, 11, 12, 14, 17, 17, 22, (....)",
            "options": ["27", "20", "22", "24"],
            "answer": "20",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 35,
            "question": "Insert the missing number. 11, 13, 17, 19, 23, 29, 31, 37, 41, (....)",
            "options": ["43", "47", "53", "51"],
            "answer": "43",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 36,
            "question": "Insert the missing number. 8, 24, 12, 36, 18, 54, (....)",
            "options": ["27", "108", "68", "72"],
            "answer": "27",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 37,
            "question": "Insert the missing number. 2, 6, 12, 20, 30, 42, 56, (....)",
            "options": ["61", "64", "72", "70"],
            "answer": "72",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 38,
            "question": "Insert the missing number. 4, -8, 16, -32, 64, (....)",
            "options": ["128", "-128", "192", "-192"],
            "answer": "-128",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 39,
            "question": "Insert the missing number. 7, 26, 63, 124, 215, 342, (....)",
            "options": ["481", "511", "391", "421"],
            "answer": "511",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 40,
            "question": "Insert the missing number. 5, 10, 13, 26, 29, 58, 61, (....)",
            "options": ["122", "64", "125", "128"],
            "answer": "122",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 41,
            "question": "Insert the missing number. 15, 31, 63, 127, 255, (....)",
            "options": ["513", "511", "517", "523"],
            "answer": "511",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 42,
            "question": "Insert the missing number. 1, 8, 27, 64, 125, 216, (....)",
            "options": ["354", "343", "392", "245"],
            "answer": "343",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 43,
            "question": "Insert the missing number. 3, 7, 6, 5, 9, 3, 12, 1, 15, (....)",
            "options": ["18", "13", "-1", "3"],
            "answer": "-1",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 44,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the series. 7, 8, 18, 57, 228, 1165, 6996",
            "options": ["8", "18", "57", "228"],
            "answer": "228",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 45,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the series. 1, 1, 2, 6, 24, 96, 720",
            "options": ["720", "96", "24", "6"],
            "answer": "96",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 46,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the series. 196, 169, 144, 121, 100, 80, 64",
            "options": ["169", "144", "121", "80"],
            "answer": "80",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 47,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the series. 445, 221, 109, 46, 25, 11, 4",
            "options": ["221", "46", "25", "11"],
            "answer": "46",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 48,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the series. 190, 166, 145, 128, 112, 100, 91",
            "options": ["166", "145", "128", "112"],
            "answer": "128",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 49,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the series. 19, 26, 33, 46, 59, 74, 91",
            "options": ["26", "33", "46", "59"],
            "answer": "33",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 50,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the series. 1, 3, 10, 21, 64, 129, 356, 777",
            "options": ["10", "21", "64", "356"],
            "answer": "356",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 51,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the series. 6, 12, 48, 100, 384, 768, 3072",
            "options": ["384", "100", "48", "12"],
            "answer": "100",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 52,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the series. 40960, 10240, 2560, 640, 200, 40, 10",
            "options": ["640", "40", "200", "2560"],
            "answer": "200",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 53,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the series. 3, 7, 15, 39, 63, 127, 255, 511",
            "options": ["15", "39", "63", "127"],
            "answer": "39",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 54,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the series. 64, 71, 80, 91, 104, 119, 135, 155",
            "options": ["71", "80", "104", "135"],
            "answer": "135",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 55,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the series. 15, 16, 34, 105, 424, 2124, 12756",
            "options": ["16", "34", "105", "2124"],
            "answer": "2124",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 56,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the series. 10, 26, 74, 218, 654, 1946, 5834",
            "options": ["26", "74", "218", "654"],
            "answer": "654",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 57,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the series. 2880, 480, 92, 24, 8, 4, 4",
            "options": ["480", "92", "24", "8"],
            "answer": "92",
            "s_id": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 58,
            "question": "Find out the wrong number in the series. 3, 7, 15, 27, 63, 127, 255",
            "options": ["7", "15", "27", "63"],
            "answer": "27",
            "s_id": 2
        }
        ]
    },






    {
        "section": "Abstract Reasoning",
        "subsection": "Coding Decoding",
        "questions": [
            {
                "id": 1,
                "question": "In a certain code language, ‘Happiness Build Upon Ourself’ is written as ‘E8L R10S M3F C6Y’ ‘Beginnings Are Always Messy’ is written as ‘D4Z R9Y X6N R5Z’ ‘Never Doubt Your Instinct’ is written as ‘Q6M S7R Q3B S6W’ ‘Learn Something New Everyday’ is written as ‘F10H V4M X7V M6O’. What is the code of the word ‘Messy’?",
                "options": ["D4Z", "R9Y", "X6N", "R5Z"],
                "answer": "X6N",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 2,
                "question": "In a certain code language, ‘Happiness Build Upon Ourself’ is written as ‘E8L R10S M3F C6Y’ ‘Beginnings Are Always Messy’ is written as ‘D4Z R9Y X6N R5Z’ ‘Never Doubt Your Instinct’ is written as ‘Q6M S7R Q3B S6W’ ‘Learn Something New Everyday’ is written as ‘F10H V4M X7V M6O’. ‘X7V’ is the code for which of the following word?",
                "options": ["Learn", "Something", "New", "Everyday"],
                "answer": "Everyday",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 3,
                "question": "In a certain code language, ‘Happiness Build Upon Ourself’ is written as ‘E8L R10S M3F C6Y’ ‘Beginnings Are Always Messy’ is written as ‘D4Z R9Y X6N R5Z’ ‘Never Doubt Your Instinct’ is written as ‘Q6M S7R Q3B S6W’ ‘Learn Something New Everyday’ is written as ‘F10H V4M X7V M6O’. What is the code of the word ‘Success’?",
                "options": ["R8H", "E7U", "R7E", "None of these"],
                "answer": "R8H",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 4,
                "question": "In a certain code language, ‘Happiness Build Upon Ourself’ is written as ‘E8L R10S M3F C6Y’ ‘Beginnings Are Always Messy’ is written as ‘D4Z R9Y X6N R5Z’ ‘Never Doubt Your Instinct’ is written as ‘Q6M S7R Q3B S6W’ ‘Learn Something New Everyday’ is written as ‘F10H V4M X7V M6O’. What is the code for the word ‘Always Doubt’?",
                "options": ["S6W D4Z", "Q3B R9Y", "Q6M X6N", "None of these"],
                "answer": "None of these",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 5,
                "question": "In a certain code language, ‘Happiness Build Upon Ourself’ is written as ‘E8L R10S M3F C6Y’ ‘Beginnings Are Always Messy’ is written as ‘D4Z R9Y X6N R5Z’ ‘Never Doubt Your Instinct’ is written as ‘Q6M S7R Q3B S6W’ ‘Learn Something New Everyday’ is written as ‘F10H V4M X7V M6O’. What is the code for the word ‘Heaven’?",
                "options": ["E7V", "M5S", "E7N", "Q6H"],
                "answer": "M5S",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 6,
                "question": "In a certain code language 'write in paper' is coded as 'la sa ka', 'read and write' is coded as 'ka na pa', and 'pen and paper' is coded as 'la na ta'. What does 'sa' stand for?",
                "options": ["Write", "Paper", "In", "And"],
                "answer": "And",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 7,
                "question": "In a certain code language 'write in paper' is coded as 'la sa ka', 'read and write' is coded as 'ka na pa', and 'pen and paper' is coded as 'la na ta'. What may be the code for 'write with pen'?",
                "options": ["ka ta sa", "ma ka ta", "ka pa ta", "la na ta"],
                "answer": "ma ka ta",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 8,
                "question": "In a certain code language 'write in paper' is coded as 'la sa ka', 'read and write' is coded as 'ka na pa', and 'pen and paper' is coded as 'la na ta'. How will 'read paper' be coded?",
                "options": ["pa la", "la na", "ka ta", "pa tu"],
                "answer": "pa la",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 9,
                "question": "In a certain code language 'write in paper' is coded as 'la sa ka', 'read and write' is coded as 'ka na pa', and 'pen and paper' is coded as 'la na ta'. What phrase will be coded as 'sa na ta'?",
                "options": ["in read write", "read and in", "pen and in", "pen red write"],
                "answer": "pen and in",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 10,
                "question": "In a certain code language 'write in paper' is coded as 'la sa ka', 'read and write' is coded as 'ka na pa', and 'pen and paper' is coded as 'la na ta'. What is the code for 'and'?",
                "options": ["sa", "na", "pa", "ka"],
                "answer": "na",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 11,
                "question": "In a certain code language ‘life is not easy’ is written as ‘pq rt av ik’ ‘meet people in life’ is written as ’av mo la ny ‘ ‘people want easy things’ is written as ‘tp ha ik mo’ ‘your want is unlimited’ is written as ‘pq ax vy ha’. What is the code for ‘things’?",
                "options": ["ha", "tp", "mo", "ik"],
                "answer": "tp",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 12,
                "question": "In a certain code language ‘life is not easy’ is written as ‘pq rt av ik’ ‘meet people in life’ is written as ’av mo la ny ‘ ‘people want easy things’ is written as ‘tp ha ik mo’ ‘your want is unlimited’ is written as ‘pq ax vy ha’. What does code ‘la’ stands for?",
                "options": ["meet", "in", "Either A or B", "Can't be determined"],
                "answer": "Either A or B",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 13,
                "question": "In a certain code language ‘life is not easy’ is written as ‘pq rt av ik’ ‘meet people in life’ is written as ’av mo la ny ‘ ‘people want easy things’ is written as ‘tp ha ik mo’ ‘your want is unlimited’ is written as ‘pq ax vy ha’. What does code ‘ha’ stands for?",
                "options": ["want", "life", "easy", "things"],
                "answer": "want",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 14,
                "question": "In a certain code language ‘life is not easy’ is written as ‘pq rt av ik’ ‘meet people in life’ is written as ’av mo la ny ‘ ‘people want easy things’ is written as ‘tp ha ik mo’ ‘your want is unlimited’ is written as ‘pq ax vy ha’. If the code for ‘life and us’ is ‘xy av ba’, then what is the code for ‘in and meet’ in the given code language?",
                "options": ["ba la ny", "av xy ny", "ny xy la", "Either A or C"],
                "answer": "Either A or C",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 15,
                "question": "In a certain code language ‘life is not easy’ is written as ‘pq rt av ik’ ‘meet people in life’ is written as ’av mo la ny ‘ ‘people want easy things’ is written as ‘tp ha ik mo’ ‘your want is unlimited’ is written as ‘pq ax vy ha’. What could be the code for ‘People need easy things?",
                "options": ["tp ik lo mo", "lo pq ax vy", "ny mo lo tp", "vy mo lo ik"],
                "answer": "tp ik lo mo",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 16,
                "question": "If ANCIENT is coded as 2516859 and NATURE is coded as 529048, then TRAIN will be coded as",
                "options": ["94285", "92456", "94265", "94168"],
                "answer": "94265",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 17,
                "question": "If each of the letters in the English alphabet is assigned odd numerical value beginning A = 1, B = 3 and so on, what will the total value of the letters for the word ‘HOTEL’?",
                "options": ["95", "115", "125", "105"],
                "answer": "115",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 18,
                "question": "If the word LEADER is coded as 20-13-9-12-13-26, how would you write LIGHT?",
                "options": ["20-16-15-17-22", "20-16-17-15-27", "20-15-16-18-23", "20-17-15-16-28"],
                "answer": "20-17-15-16-28",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 19,
                "question": "If each of the letters in the English alphabet is assigned an even numerical value by giving A = 2, B = 4 and so on. What would be the total value of the letters for the word LADY when similarly coded?",
                "options": ["82", "74", "72", "84"],
                "answer": "84",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 20,
                "question": "Rewrite the word POWDER in the numeric form by writing its first three letters in the reverse order and then next three letters in the reverse order by substituting O by 7, D by 2, W by 5, E by 1, P by 3, R by 6.",
                "options": ["573612", "576312", "657312", "None of these"],
                "answer": "576312",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 21,
                "question": "If B is coded as 8, F is coded as 6, Q is coded as 4, D is coded as 7, T is coded as 2, M is coded as 3 and K is coded as 5, then what is the coded form of BFKMQT?",
                "options": ["856342", "658342", "865243", "865342"],
                "answer": "865342",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 22,
                "question": "If DRIVER = 12, PEDESTRIAN = 20, EGG = 6, then SHOP = ?",
                "options": ["8", "10", "16", "4"],
                "answer": "8",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 23,
                "question": "If O = 16, FOR = 42, then what is BACK equal to?",
                "options": ["20", "21", "22", "None of these"],
                "answer": "21",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 24,
                "question": "If work is coded as 4 – 12 – 9 – 16. then how will you code MAGGI?",
                "options": ["14 – 26 – 20 – 20 – 18", "14 – 26 – 21 – 21 – 19", "15 – 26 – 20 – 20 – 18", "15 – 26 – 21 – 21 – 19"],
                "answer": "14-26-20-20-18",
                "s_id": 3
            },
            {
                "id": 25,
                "question": "If D = 4 and FAT = 9, how will you code PIN = ?",
                "options": ["13", "10", "11", "None of these"],
                "answer": "13",
                "s_id": 3
            }
        ]
    },
    

    
    {
        "section": "Abstract Reasoning",
        "subsection": "Series Completion",
        "questions": [
            {
                "id": 1,
                "question": "Complete the series: SCD, TEF, UGH, ____, WKL",
                "options": ["CMN", "UJI", "VIJ", "IJT"],
                "answer": "VIJ",
                "s_id": 4
            },
            {
                "id": 2,
                "question": "Complete the series: B2CD, _____, BCD4, B5CD, BC6D",
                "options": ["B2C2D", "BC3D", "B2C3D", "BCD7"],
                "answer": "BC3D",
                "s_id": 4
            },
            {
                "id": 3,
                "question": "Complete the series: FAG, GAF, HAI, IAH, ____",
                "options": ["JAK", "HAL", "HAK", "JAI"],
                "answer": "JAK",
                "s_id": 4
            },
            {
                "id": 4,
                "question": "Complete the series: ELFA, GLHA, ILJA, _____, MLNA",
                "options": ["OLPA", "KLMA", "LLMA", "KLLA"],
                "answer": "KLLA",
                "s_id": 4
            },
            {
                "id": 5,
                "question": "Complete the series: CMM, EOO, GQQ, _____, KUU",
                "options": ["GRR", "GSS", "ISS", "ITT"],
                "answer": "ISS",
                "s_id": 4
            },
            {
                "id": 6,
                "question": "Complete the series: ZA5, Y4B, XC6, W3D, _____",
                "options": ["E7V", "V2E", "VE5", "VE7"],
                "answer": "VE7",
                "s_id": 4
            },
            {
                "id": 7,
                "question": "Complete the series: QPO, NML, KJI, _____, EDC",
                "options": ["HGF", "CAB", "JKL", "GHI"],
                "answer": "HGF",
                "s_id": 4
            },
            {
                "id": 8,
                "question": "Complete the series: JAK, KBL, LCM, MDN, _____",
                "options": ["OEP", "NEO", "MEN", "PFQ"],
                "answer": "NEO",
                "s_id": 4
            },
            {
                "id": 9,
                "question": "Complete the series: BCB, DED, FGF, HIH, ___",
                "options": ["JKJ", "HJH", "IJI", "JHJ"],
                "answer": "JKJ",
                "s_id": 4
            },
            {
                "id": 10,
                "question": "Complete the series: P5QR, P4QS, P3QT, _____, P1QV",
                "options": ["PQW", "PQV2", "P2QU", "PQ3U"],
                "answer": "P2QU",
                "s_id": 4
            },
            {
                "id": 11,
                "question": "Complete the series: QAR, RAS, SAT, TAU, _____",
                "options": ["UAV", "UAT", "TAS", "TAT"],
                "answer": "UAV",
                "s_id": 4
            },
            {
                "id": 12,
                "question": "Complete the series: DEF, DEF2, DE2F2, _____, D2E2F3",
                "options": ["DEF3", "D3EF3", "D2E3F", "D2E2F2"],
                "answer": "D2E2F2",
                "s_id": 4
            },
            {
                "id": 13,
                "question": "Complete the series: A, C, E, G, __?",
                "options": ["I", "H", "F", "K"],
                "answer": "I",
                "s_id": 4
            },
            {
                "id": 14,
                "question": "Complete the series: *, $$, ***, $$$$$, __?",
                "options": ["*****", "****", "******", "$$$$$$"],
                "answer": "*****",
                "s_id": 4
            },
            {
                "id": 15,
                "question": "Complete the series: Y, W, U, S, Q, __, M.",
                "options": ["L", "K", "N", "O"],
                "answer": "N",
                "s_id": 4
            }
        ]
    },
    
        
    {
        "section": "Critical Reasoning",
        "subsection": "Data Sufficiency",
        "questions": [
            {
                "id": 1,
                "question": "In which year was Rahul born?",
                "statements": [
                    "I. Rahul at present is 25 years younger to his mother.",
                    "II. Rahul's brother, who was born in 1964, is 35 years younger to his mother."
                ],
                "options": [
                    "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                    "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                    "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                    "Both I and II are sufficient"
                ],
                "answer": "Both I and II are sufficient",
                "s_id": 1
            },
            {
                "id": 2,
                "question": "What will be the total weight of 10 poles, each of the same weight?",
                "statements": [
                    "I. One-fourth of the weight of each pole is 5 kg.",
                    "II. The total weight of three poles is 20 kilograms more than the total weight of two poles."
                ],
                "options": [
                    "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                    "Either I or II is sufficient",
                    "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                    "Both I and II are sufficient"
                ],
                "answer": "Either I or II is sufficient",
                "s_id": 1
            },
            {
                "id": 3,
                "question": "How many children does M have?",
                "statements": [
                    "I. H is the only daughter of X who is wife of M.",
                    "II. K and J are brothers of M."
                ],
                "options": [
                    "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                    "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                    "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                    "Both I and II are sufficient"
                ],
                "answer": "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                "s_id": 1
            },
            {
                "id": 4,
                "question": "How much was the total sale of the company?",
                "statements": [
                    "I. The company sold 8000 units of product A each costing Rs. 25.",
                    "II. This company has no other product line."
                ],
                "options": [
                    "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                    "Either I or II is sufficient",
                    "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                    "Both I and II are sufficient"
                ],
                "answer": "Both I and II are sufficient",
                "s_id": 1
            },
            {
                "id": 5,
                "question": "The last Sunday of March, 2006 fell on which date?",
                "statements": [
                    "I. The first Sunday of that month fell on 5th.",
                    "II. The last day of that month was Friday."
                ],
                "options": [
                    "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                    "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                    "Either I or II is sufficient",
                    "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                    "Both I and II are sufficient"
                ],
                "answer": "Either I or II is sufficient",
                "s_id": 1
            },
            {
                "id": 6,
                "question": "What is the code for 'sky' in the code language?",
                "statements": [
                    "I. In the code language, 'sky is clear' is written as 'de ra fa'.",
                    "II. In the same code language, 'make it clear' is written as 'de ga jo'."
                ],
                "options": [
                    "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                    "Either I or II is sufficient",
                    "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                    "Both I and II are sufficient"
                ],
                "answer": "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                "s_id": 1
            },
            {
                "id": 7,
                "question": "How many children are there between P and Q in a row of children?",
                "statements": [
                    "I. P is fifteenth from the left in the row.",
                    "II. Q is exactly in the middle and there are ten children towards his right."
                ],
                "options": [
                    "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                    "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                    "Either I or II is sufficient",
                    "Both I and II are sufficient"
                ],
                "answer": "Both I and II are sufficient",
                "s_id": 1
            },
            {
                "id": 8,
                "question": "How is T related to K?",
                "statements": [
                    "I. R's sister J has married T's brother L, who is the only son of his parents.",
                    "II. K is the only daughter of L and J."
                ],
                "options": [
                    "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                    "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                    "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                    "Both I and II are sufficient"
                ],
                "answer": "Both I and II are sufficient",
                "s_id": 1
            },
            {
                "id": 9,
                "question": "How is J related to P?",
                "statements": [
                    "I. M is brother of P and T is sister of P.",
                    "II. P's mother is married to J's husband who has one son and two daughters."
                ],
                "options": [
                    "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                    "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                    "Either I or II is sufficient",
                    "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                    "Both I and II are sufficient"
                ],
                "answer": "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                "s_id": 1
            },
            {
                "id": 10,
                "question": "How is X related to Y?",
                "statements": [
                    "I. Y and Z are children of D who is wife of X.",
                    "II. R's sister X is married to Y's father."
                ],
                "options": [
                    "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                    "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                    "Either I or II is sufficient",
                    "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                    "Both I and II are sufficient"
                ],
                "answer": "Either I or II is sufficient",
                "s_id": 1
            },
            {
                "id": 11,
                "question": "Among T, V, B, E and C, who is the third from the top when arranged in the descending order of their weights?",
                "statements": [
                    "I. B is heavier than T and C and is less heavier than V who is not the heaviest.",
                    "II. C is heavier than only T."
                ],
                "options": [
                    "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                    "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                    "Either I or II is sufficient",
                    "Neither I nor II is sufficient"
                ],
                "answer": "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                "s_id": 1
            },
            {
                "id": 12,
                "question": "Which word in the code language means 'flower'?",
                "statements": [
                    "I. 'de fu la pane' means 'rose flower is beautiful' and 'la quiz' means 'beautiful tree'.",
                    "II. 'de la chin' means 'red rose flower' and 'pa chin' means 'red tea'."
                ],
                "options": [
                    "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                    "Either I or II is sufficient",
                    "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                    "Both I and II are sufficient"
                ],
                "answer": "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                "s_id": 1
            },
            {
                "id": 13,
                "question": "How many students in a class play football?",
                "statements": [
                    "I. Only boys play football.",
                    "II. There are forty boys and thirty girls in the class."
                ],
                "options": [
                    "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                    "Either I or II is sufficient",
                    "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                    "Both I and II are sufficient"
                ],
                "answer": "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                "s_id": 1
            },
            {
                "id": 14,
                "question": "Who is C's partner in a game of cards involving four players A, B, C and D?",
                "statements": [
                    "I. D is sitting opposite to A.",
                    "II. B is sitting right of A and left of D."
                ],
                "options": [
                    "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                    "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                    "Either I or II is sufficient",
                    "Neither I nor II is sufficient"
                ],
                "answer": "Both I and II are sufficient",
                "s_id": 1
            },
            {
                "id": 15,
                "question": "How many total employees are there in the organization?",
                "statements": [
                    "I. There are 40 male employees and 60 female employees.",
                    "II. The total number of employees is three times the number of male employees."
                ],
                "options": [
                    "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                    "Either I or II is sufficient",
                    "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                    "Both I and II are sufficient"
                ],
                "answer": "Both I and II are sufficient",
                "s_id": 1
            },
    

                    {
                        "id": 16,
                        "question": "How is Sulekha related to Nandini?",
                        "statements": [
                            "I. Nandini is the only sister of Sulekha's father.",
                            "II. Sulekha has one brother who is married to Nandini."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                            "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                            "Either I or II is sufficient",
                            "Neither I nor II is sufficient"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Either I or II is sufficient",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 17,
                        "question": "Can Ritesh retire from office X in January 2006, with full pension benefits?",
                        "statements": [
                            "I. Ritesh has served the office for more than 30 years.",
                            "II. The retirement age is 60 years and Ritesh is 58 years old."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                            "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                            "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                            "Both I and II are sufficient"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II are sufficient",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 18,
                        "question": "What is the code for 'or' in the code language?",
                        "statements": [
                            "I. 'and or not' is coded as 'ra fa ta'.",
                            "II. 'or not yes' is coded as 'ta la pa'."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                            "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                            "Either I or II is sufficient",
                            "Both I and II are sufficient"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Either I or II is sufficient",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 19,
                        "question": "Madan is elder than Kamal and Sharad is younger than Arvind. Who among them is the youngest?",
                        "statements": [
                            "I. Arvind is elder than Kamal.",
                            "II. Madan is elder than Arvind."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                            "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                            "Either I or II is sufficient",
                            "Neither I nor II is sufficient"
                        ],
                        "answer": "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 20,
                        "question": "On which date in August was Kapil born?",
                        "statements": [
                            "I. Kapil was born on a Monday.",
                            "II. Kapil's birthday falls on the 20th of August."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                            "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                            "Either I or II is sufficient",
                            "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                            "Both I and II are sufficient"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II are sufficient",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 21,
                        "question": "What is Gagan's age?",
                        "statements": [
                            "I. Gagan, Vimal and Kunal are all of the same age.",
                            "II. Total age of Vimal, Kunal and Anil is 32 years and Anil is as old as Vimal and Kunal together."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                            "Either I or II is sufficient",
                            "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                            "Both I and II are sufficient"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II are sufficient",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 22,
                        "question": "In a certain code, '13' means 'stop smoking' and '59' means 'injurious habit'. What do '9' and '5' mean respectively in that code?",
                        "statements": [
                            "I. '157' means 'stop bad habit'.",
                            "II. '839' means 'smoking is injurious'."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                            "Either I or II is sufficient",
                            "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                            "Both I and II are sufficient"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Either I or II is sufficient",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 23,
                        "question": "How much money do Vivek and Suman have together?",
                        "statements": [
                            "I. Suman has 20 rupees less than what Tarun has.",
                            "II. Vivek has 30 rupees more than what Tarun has."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                            "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                            "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                            "Both I and II are sufficient"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 24,
                        "question": "Among Monika, Anita, Sonal, Ratna and Tanvy, who came last for the programme?",
                        "statements": [
                            "I. Monika came after Anita but not after Tanvy.",
                            "II. Ratna came after Tanvy but not after Sonal."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                            "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                            "Either I or II is sufficient",
                            "Both I and II are sufficient"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II are sufficient",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 25,
                        "question": "Who among P, Q, R, S and T is the lightest?",
                        "statements": [
                            "I. R is heavier than Q and T but lighter than S.",
                            "II. S is not the heaviest."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                            "Either I or II is sufficient",
                            "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                            "Both I and II are sufficient"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 26,
                        "question": "How is T related to K?",
                        "statements": [
                            "I. K has two sons; one of the sons is A.",
                            "II. The mother of T has only two sons - A and B."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                            "Either I or II is sufficient",
                            "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                            "Both I and II are sufficient"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II are sufficient",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 27,
                        "question": "What is the shortest distance between Devipur and Durgapur?",
                        "statements": [
                            "I. Durgapur is 20 kms away from Rampur.",
                            "II. Devipur is 15 kms away from Rampur."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                            "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                            "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                            "Both I and II are sufficient"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 28,
                        "question": "How is A related to D?",
                        "statements": [
                            "I. B is the brother of A.",
                            "II. B is D's son."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                            "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                            "Either I or II is sufficient",
                            "Neither I nor II is sufficient"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 29,
                        "question": "Manoj, Prabhakar, Akash and Kamal are four friends. Who among them is the heaviest?",
                        "statements": [
                            "I. Prabhakar is heavier than Manoj and Kamal but lighter than Akash.",
                            "II. Manoj is lighter than Prabhakar and Akash but heavier than Kamal."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                            "Either I or II is sufficient",
                            "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                            "Both I and II are sufficient"
                        ],
                        "answer": "I alone is sufficient while II alone is not sufficient",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 30,
                        "question": "Vinod's and Javed's salaries are in the proportion of 4 : 3 respectively. What is Vinod's salary?",
                        "statements": [
                            "I. Javed's salary is 75% that of Vinod's salary.",
                            "II. Javed's salary is Rs 4500."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                            "Either I or II is sufficient",
                            "Neither I nor II is sufficient",
                            "Both I and II are sufficient"
                        ],
                        "answer": "II alone is sufficient while I alone is not sufficient",
                        "s_id": 1
                    }
            ]
        },




            
        {
                "section": "Critical Reasoning",
                "subsection": "Syllogism",
                "questions": [
                    {
                        "id": 1,
                        "question": "As Diwali festival is approaching Vikrant goes to his father with a view to convince him for buying crackers for Vikrant. He says, “Dad! My friend Rahul likes crackers very much.” His father replies, “Son, all crackers are harmful and all the harmful things make this world a worse place to live in.” He continued, “Even sweets are harmful.” “But Dad, Rahul is an intelligent boy.” argues Vikrant. His father replies, “I do acknowledge too that Rahul is an intelligent boy, but alas! Some intelligent boys are not wise.” With a dejected face, Rahul leaves for his tuition classes. Which of the following conclusions definitely follows?",
                        "statements": [
                            "Some sweets are not harmful.",
                            "All harmful things are crackers.",
                            "Rahul does like sweets.",
                            "Rahul likes harmful things."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Rahul likes harmful things",
                            "Some sweets are not harmful",
                            "All harmful things are crackers",
                            "Rahul does like sweets"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Rahul likes harmful things",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 2,
                        "question": "Which of the following conclusions is possibly true?",
                        "statements": [
                            "All intelligent boys are wise.",
                            "All wise are intelligent boys.",
                            "No cracker is liked by Rahul.",
                            "Both A and C"
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "All wise are intelligent boys",
                            "All intelligent boys are wise",
                            "No cracker is liked by Rahul",
                            "Both A and C"
                        ],
                        "answer": "All wise are intelligent boys",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 3,
                        "question": "Which of the following conclusions doesn’t follow?",
                        "statements": [
                            "All intelligent boys being Rahul is a possibility.",
                            "Rahul may not be wise.",
                            "Everything that makes this world a worse place to live in is harmful.",
                            "Some crackers are liked by Rahul."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "All intelligent boys being Rahul is a possibility",
                            "Rahul may not be wise",
                            "Everything that makes this world a worse place to live in is harmful",
                            "Some crackers are liked by Rahul"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Everything that makes this world a worse place to live in is harmful",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 4,
                        "question": "Which of the following statements is redundant in deriving the conclusion – “Some who are intelligent like harmful things very much”?",
                        "statements": [
                            "Some intelligent boys are not wise.",
                            "Rahul likes crackers very much.",
                            "All crackers are harmful.",
                            "Rahul is an intelligent boy."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Some intelligent boys are not wise",
                            "Rahul likes crackers very much",
                            "All crackers are harmful",
                            "Rahul is an intelligent boy"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Some intelligent boys are not wise",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 5,
                        "question": "Which of the following statements is required to give us the conclusion – “Some harmful things are not snacks.”?",
                        "statements": [
                            "Some crackers are not snacks.",
                            "Some snacks are not crackers.",
                            "No sweets are crackers.",
                            "No cracker is snack."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Some crackers are not snacks",
                            "Some snacks are not crackers",
                            "No sweets are crackers",
                            "No cracker is snack"
                        ],
                        "answer": "No cracker is snack",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 6,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Some actors are singers. All the singers are dancers.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some actors are dancers.",
                            "No singer is actor."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                            "Either (1) or (2) follows",
                            "Neither (1) nor (2) follows",
                            "Both (1) and (2) follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 7,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "All the harmoniums are instruments. All the instruments are flutes.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "All the flutes are instruments.",
                            "All the harmoniums are flutes."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                            "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                            "Either (1) or (2) follows",
                            "Both (1) and (2) follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 8,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Some mangoes are yellow. Some tixo are mangoes.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some mangoes are green.",
                            "Tixo is a yellow."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                            "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                            "Either (1) or (2) follows",
                            "Neither (1) nor (2) follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither (1) nor (2) follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 9,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Some ants are parrots. All the parrots are apples.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "All the apples are parrots.",
                            "Some ants are apples."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                            "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                            "Either (1) or (2) follows",
                            "Neither (1) nor (2) follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 10,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Some papers are pens. All the pencils are pens.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some pens are pencils.",
                            "Some pens are papers."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                            "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                            "Either (1) or (2) follows",
                            "Both (1) and (2) follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both (1) and (2) follow",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 11,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "All the actors are girls. All the girls are beautiful.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "All the actors are beautiful.",
                            "Some girls are actors."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                            "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                            "Neither (1) nor (2) follows",
                            "Both (1) and (2) follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both (1) and (2) follow",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 12,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "All the windows are doors. No door is a wall.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some windows are walls.",
                            "No wall is a door."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                            "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                            "Either (1) or (2) follows",
                            "Both (1) and (2) follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 13,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "All cups are books. All books are shirts.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some cups are not shirts.",
                            "Some shirts are cups."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                            "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                            "Neither (1) nor (2) follows",
                            "Both (1) and (2) follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 14,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Some cows are crows. Some crows are elephants.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some cows are elephants.",
                            "All crows are elephants."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                            "Either (1) or (2) follows",
                            "Neither (1) nor (2) follows",
                            "Both (1) and (2) follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither (1) nor (2) follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 15,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "All birds are animals. Some animals are mammals.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some birds are mammals.",
                            "Some mammals are birds."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                            "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                            "Either (1) or (2) follows",
                            "Both (1) and (2) follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both (1) and (2) follow",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },

            
                    {
                        "id": 16,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Some dogs are bats. Some bats are cats.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some dogs are cats.",
                            "Some cats are dogs."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                            "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                            "Either (1) or (2) follows",
                            "Neither (1) nor (2) follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither (1) nor (2) follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 17,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "All the trucks are flies. Some scooters are flies.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "All the trucks are scooters.",
                            "Some scooters are trucks."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                            "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                            "Neither (1) nor (2) follows",
                            "Both (1) and (2) follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither (1) nor (2) follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 18,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "All buildings are chalks. No chalk is toffee.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "No building is toffee.",
                            "All chalks are buildings."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                            "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                            "Either (1) or (2) follows",
                            "Neither (1) nor (2) follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 19,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "All cars are cats. All fans are cats.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "All cars are fans.",
                            "Some fans are cars."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) conclusion follows",
                            "Only (2) conclusion follows",
                            "Either (1) or (2) follows",
                            "Neither (1) nor (2) follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither (1) nor (2) follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 20,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "No door is dog. All the dogs are cats.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "No door is cat.",
                            "No cat is door.",
                            "Some cats are dogs.",
                            "All the cats are dogs."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (2) and (4)",
                            "Only (1) and (3)",
                            "Only (3) and (4)",
                            "Only (3)"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only (3)",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 21,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "All green are blue. All blue are white.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some blue are green.",
                            "Some white are green.",
                            "Some green are not white.",
                            "All white are blue."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) and (2)",
                            "Only (1) and (3)",
                            "Only (1) and (4)",
                            "Only (2) and (4)"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only (1) and (2)",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 22,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "All men are vertebrates. Some mammals are vertebrates.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "All men are mammals.",
                            "All mammals are men.",
                            "Some vertebrates are mammals.",
                            "All vertebrates are men."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (4)",
                            "Only (2)",
                            "Only (3)",
                            "Only (1) and (3)"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only (3)",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 23,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "All the phones are scales. All the scales are calculators.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "All the calculators are scales.",
                            "All the phones are calculators.",
                            "All the scales are phones.",
                            "Some calculators are phones."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (1) and (4)",
                            "Only (3) and (4)",
                            "Only (2) and (4)",
                            "Only (1) and (2)"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only (2) and (4)",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 24,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Some tables are T.V. Some T.V. are radios.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some tables are radios.",
                            "Some radios are tables.",
                            "All the radios are T.V.",
                            "All the T.V. are tables."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only (2) and (4)",
                            "Only (1) and (3)",
                            "Only (1) and (4)",
                            "None of the four."
                        ],
                        "answer": "None of the four.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 25,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Some oranges are apples. All lemons are apples. No apple is guava.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some oranges are lemons.",
                            "All guavas being lemon is a possibility.",
                            "No orange is a lemon."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only C3 follows",
                            "Either C1 or C3 follows",
                            "Only C2 and C3 follow",
                            "All follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Either C1 or C3 follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 26,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "A few mechanics are not plumbers. All plumbers are qualified. No qualified is skilled.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "No skilled is a plumber.",
                            "No mechanic is skilled.",
                            "Some plumbers are not mechanics."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only C1 follows",
                            "Either C1 or C2 follows",
                            "Only C2 and C3 follow",
                            "All follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only C1 follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 27,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "No cycle is tyre. Not a single tyre is tube. Every tube is puncture.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some punctures which are tubes are cycles as well.",
                            "No cycle is a tube.",
                            "Some punctures are not tyres."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only C3 follows",
                            "Either C1 or C2 follows",
                            "Only C2 and C3 follow",
                            "All follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only C3 follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 28,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "No panther is jaguar. Not a single jaguar is puma. Every puma is cheetah.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some cheetah which are puma are panther as well.",
                            "No panther is a puma.",
                            "Some cheetah are not jaguar."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only C3 follows",
                            "Either C1 or C2 follows",
                            "Only C2 and C3 follow",
                            "All follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only C3 follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 29,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "A few poets are not poetesses. All poetesses are serious. No serious is diligent.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "No diligent is a poetess.",
                            "No poet is diligent.",
                            "Some poetesses are not poets."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only C1 follows",
                            "Either C1 or C2 follows",
                            "Only C2 and C3 follow",
                            "All follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only C1 follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 30,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "No bike is a bus. All buses are trucks. All trucks are cars.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "All buses are cars.",
                            "At least some cars are trucks."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Only I follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II follow",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 31,
                        "question": "Read the conclusions and then decide which of the given conclusions logically follows from the two given statements, disregarding commonly known facts.",
                        "statements": "No apple is peach. All peaches are pineapples.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "All mangoes are pineapples.",
                            "Some pineapples are apples."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Only I follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 32,
                        "question": "Read the conclusions and then decide which of the given conclusions logically follows from the two given statements, disregarding commonly known facts.",
                        "statements": "Some lions are tigers. Some tigers are panthers. All panthers are elephants.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some elephants are tigers.",
                            "All lions being elephants is a possibility."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Only I follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II follow",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 33,
                        "question": "Read the conclusions and then decide which of the given conclusions logically follows from the two given statements, disregarding commonly known facts.",
                        "statements": "At least some Europeans are British. Every European is an American. No American is an African.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "All Americans being British is a possibility.",
                            "Some Europeans can be Africans as well.",
                            "No African is a British."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only I follows",
                            "I and III follow",
                            "I and II follow",
                            "All I, II and III follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only I follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 34,
                        "question": "Read the conclusions and then decide which of the given conclusions logically follows from the two given statements, disregarding commonly known facts.",
                        "statements": "No grasshopper is an insect. No insect is a bug. All bugs are moths.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some bugs may be grasshoppers.",
                            "All moths being insects is a possibility.",
                            "No bug is a grasshopper."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Either I or III follows",
                            "I and III follow",
                            "Only I follows",
                            "All I, II and III follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only I follows",
                        "s_id": 2
                    }
                ]
            },
            






            {
                "section": "Critical Reasoning",
                "subsection": "Statement Conclusion",
                "questions": [
                    {
                        "id": 1,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "In a one day cricket match, the total runs made by a team were 200. Out of these 160 runs were made by spinners.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "80% of the team consists of spinners.",
                            "The opening batsmen were spinners."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 2,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "The old order changed yielding place to new.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Change is the law of nature.",
                            "Discard old ideas because they are old."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion I follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 3,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Government has spoiled many top ranking financial institutions by appointing bureaucrats as Directors of these institutions.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Government should appoint Directors of the financial institutes taking into consideration the expertise of the person in the area of finance.",
                            "The Director of the financial institute should have expertise commensurate with the financial work carried out by the institute."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II follow",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 4,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Population increase coupled with depleting resources is going to be the scenario of many developing countries in days to come.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "The population of developing countries will not continue to increase in future.",
                            "It will be very difficult for the governments of developing countries to provide its people decent quality of life."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 5,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Prime age school-going children in urban India have now become avid as well as more regular viewers of television, even in households without a TV. As a result there has been an alarming decline in the extent of readership of newspapers.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Method of increasing the readership of newspapers should be devised.",
                            "A team of experts should be sent to other countries to study the impact of TV. on the readership of newspapers."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 6,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "In Japan, the incidence of stomach cancer is very high, while that of bowel cancer is very low. But Japanese immigrate to Hawaii, this is reversed - the rate of bowel cancer increases but the rate of stomach cancer is reduced in the next generation. All this is related to nutrition - the diets of Japanese in Hawaii are different than those in Japan.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "The same diet as in Hawaii should be propagated in Japan also.",
                            "Bowel cancer is less severe than stomach cancer."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 7,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "The Government run company had asked its employees to declare their income and assets but it has been strongly resisted by employees union and no employee is going to declare his income.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "The employees of this company do not seem to have any additional undisclosed income besides their salary.",
                            "The employees union wants all senior officers to declare their income first."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 8,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Monitoring has become an integral part in the planning of social development programmes. It is recommended that Management Information System be developed for all programmes. This is likely to give a feedback on the performance of the functionaries and the efficacy with which services are being delivered.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "All the social development programmes should be evaluated.",
                            "There is a need to monitor the performance of workers."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II follow",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 9,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "The T.V. programmes, telecast specially for women are packed with a variety of recipes and household hints. A major portion of magazines for women also contains the items mentioned above.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Women are not interested in other things.",
                            "An average woman's primary interest lies in home and specially in the kitchen."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 10,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "The distance of 900 km by road between Bombay and Jafra will be reduced to 280 km by sea. This will lead to a saving of Rs. 7.92 crores per annum on fuel.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Transportation by sea is cheaper than that by road.",
                            "Fuel must be saved to the greatest extent."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 11,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "The manager humiliated Sachin in the presence of his colleagues.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "The manager did not like Sachin.",
                            "Sachin was not popular with his colleagues."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 12,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Women's organisations in India have welcomed the amendment of the Industrial Employment Rules 1946 to curb sexual harassment at the work place.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Sexual harassment of women at work place is more prevalent in India as compared to other developed countries.",
                            "Many organisations in India will stop recruiting women to avoid such problems."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 13,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Nation X faced growing international opposition for its decision to explode eight nuclear weapons at its test site.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "The citizens of the nation favoured the decision.",
                            "Some powerful countries do not want other nations to become as powerful as they are."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 14,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "In a highly centralised power structure, in which even senior cabinet ministers are prepared to reduce themselves to pathetic countries or yesmen airing views that are primarily intended to anticipate or reflect the Prime Minister's own performances, there can be no place for any consensus that is quite different from real or contrived unanimity of opinion, expressed through a well-orchestrated endorsement of the leader's actions.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "The Ministers play safe by not giving anti-government views.",
                            "The Prime Minister does not encourage his colleagues to render their own views."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion I follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 15,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "National Aluminium Company has moved India from a position of shortage to self-sufficiency in the metal.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Previously, India had to import aluminium.",
                            "With this speed, it can soon become a foreign exchange earner."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II follow",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
            
                    {
                        "id": 16,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Jade plant has thick leaves and it requires little water.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "All plants with thick leaves require little water.",
                            "Jade plants may be grown in places where water is not in abundance."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 17,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Use 'Kraft' colours. They add colour to our life. - An advertisement.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Catchy slogans do not attract people.",
                            "People like dark colours."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 18,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "All those political prisoners were released on bail who had gone to jail for reasons other than political dharnas. Bail was not granted to persons involved in murders.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "No political-prisoner had committed murder.",
                            "Some politicians were not arrested."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion I follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 19,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Modern man influences his destiny by the choice he makes unlike in the past.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Earlier there were fewer options available to man.",
                            "There was no desire in the past to influence the destiny."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion I follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 20,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Water supply in wards A and B of the city will be affected by about 50% on Friday because repairing work of the main lines is to be carried out.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "The residents in these wards should economise on water on Friday.",
                            "The residents in these wards should store some water on the previous day."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II follow",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 21,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "People who speak too much against dowry are those who had taken it themselves.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "It is easier said than done.",
                            "People have double standards."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II follow",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 22,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "The national norm is 100 beds per thousand populations but in this state, 150 beds per thousand are available in the hospitals.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Our national norm is appropriate.",
                            "The state's health system is taking adequate care in this regard."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 23,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Our securities investments carry market risk. Consult your investment advisor or agent before investing.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "One should not invest in securities.",
                            "The investment advisor calculates the market risk with certainty."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 24,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Money plays a vital role in politics.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "The poor can never become politicians.",
                            "All the rich men take part in politics."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 25,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Vegetable prices are soaring in the market.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Vegetables are becoming a rare commodity.",
                            "People cannot eat vegetables."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 26,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "The serious accident in which a person was run down by a car yesterday had again focused attention on the most unsatisfactory state of roads.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "The accident that occurred was fatal.",
                            "Several accidents have so far taken place because of unsatisfactory state of roads."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II follow",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 27,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "In a recent survey report, it has been stated that those who undertake physical exercise for at least half an hour a day are less prone to have any heart ailments.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Moderate level of physical exercise is necessary for leading a healthy life.",
                            "All people who do desk-bound jobs definitely suffer from heart ailments."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion I follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 28,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "A bird in hand is worth two in the bush.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "We should be content with what we have.",
                            "We should not crave for what is not."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II follow",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 29,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "This world is neither good nor evil; each man manufactures a world for himself.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Some people find this world quite good.",
                            "Some people find this world quite bad."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II follow",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 30,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "The eligibility for admission to the course is minimum second class Master's degree. However, the candidates who have appeared for the final year examination of Master's degree can also apply.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "All candidates who have yet to get their Master's degree will be there in the list of selected candidates.",
                            "All candidates having obtained second class Master's degree will be there in the list of selected candidates."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
            
                    {
                        "id": 31,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Any student who does not behave properly while in the school brings bad name to himself and also for the school.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Such student should be removed from the school.",
                            "Stricter discipline does not improve behaviour of the students."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 32,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "A Corporate General Manager asked four managers to either submit their resignations by the next day or face termination orders from service. Three of them had submitted their resignations by that evening.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "The next day, the remaining manager would also resign.",
                            "The General Manager would terminate his services the next day."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Either I or II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 33,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Only good singers are invited in the conference. No one without sweet voice is a good singer.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "All invited singers in the conference have sweet voice.",
                            "Those singers who do not have sweet voice are not invited in the conference."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II follow",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 34,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "To cultivate interest in reading, the school has made it compulsory from June this year for each student to read two books per week and submit a weekly report on the books.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Interest in reading can be created by force.",
                            "Some students will eventually develop interest in reading."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 35,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Applications of applicants who do not fulfil eligibility criteria and/or who do not submit applications before last date will be summarily rejected and will not be called for the written test.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Those who are called for the written test are those who fulfil eligibility criteria and have submitted their applications before last date.",
                            "Written test will be held only after scrutiny of applications."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II follow",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 36,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Recent trends also indicate that the number of child migrants in large cities is increasing. These children leave their families to join the ranks of urban poor doing odd jobs in markets, workshops, hotels or in service sectors.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Migration to big cities should be checked.",
                            "The plight of poor children should be thoroughly studied."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I nor II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 37,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "No country is absolutely self-dependent these days.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "It is impossible to grow and produce all that a country needs.",
                            "Countrymen in general have become lazy."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion I follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 38,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "The percentage of the national income shared by the top 10 percent of households in India is 35.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "When an economy grows fast, concentration of wealth in certain pockets of population takes place.",
                            "The national income is unevenly distributed in India."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 39,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Players who break various records in a fair way get special prizes. Player X broke the world record but was found to be under the influence of a prohibited drug.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "X will get the special prize.",
                            "X will not get the special prize."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 40,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Company X has marketed the product. Go ahead; purchase it if price and quality are your considerations.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "The product must be good in quality.",
                            "The price of the product must be reasonable."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II follow",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 41,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Quality has a price tag. India is allocating lots of funds to education.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Quality of education in India would improve soon.",
                            "Funding alone can enhance quality of education."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion I follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 42,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Although we have rating agencies like Crisil, ICRA, there is demand to have a separate rating agency for IT companies to protect investors.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Assessment of financial worth of IT companies calls for separate set of skills, insight and competencies.",
                            "Now the investors investing in IT companies will get protection of their investment."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion I follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 43,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "The standard of education in private schools is much better than Municipal and Zila Parishad-run schools.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "The Municipal and Zila Parishad should make serious efforts to improve standard of their schools.",
                            "All Municipal and Zila Parishad schools should be closed immediately."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion I follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 44,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "All the organised persons find time for rest. Sunita, in spite of her very busy schedule, finds time for rest.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Sunita is an organised person.",
                            "Sunita is an industrious person."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I nor II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Both I and II follow",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 45,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Domestic demand has been increasing faster than the production of indigenous crude oil.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Crude oil must be imported.",
                            "Domestic demand should be reduced."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Either I or II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 46,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "He stressed the need to stop the present examination system and its replacement by other methods which would measure the real merit of the students.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Examinations should be abolished.",
                            "The present examination system does not measure the real merit of the students."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Both I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Only conclusion II follows",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 47,
                        "question": "According to given statements, choose the conclusions that follow.",
                        "statements": "Fashion is a form of ugliness so intolerable that we have to alter it every six months.",
                        "conclusions": [
                            "Fashion designers do not understand the concept of beauty.",
                            "Fashion is not meant to last."
                        ],
                        "options": [
                            "Only conclusion I follows",
                            "Only conclusion II follows",
                            "Either I or II follows",
                            "Neither I and II follow"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Neither I and II follow",
                        "s_id": 3
                    }
                ]
            },
     






            {
                "section": "English Ability",
                "subsection": "Synonyms and Antonyms",
                "questions": [
                    {
                        "id": 1,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "ENORMOUS",
                        "options": ["Soft", "Average", "Tiny", "Weak"],
                        "answer": "Tiny",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 2,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "COMMISSIONED",
                        "options": ["Started", "Closed", "Finished", "Terminated"],
                        "answer": "Terminated",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 3,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "ARTIFICIAL",
                        "options": ["Red", "Natural", "Truthful", "Solid"],
                        "answer": "Natural",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 4,
                        "word": "EXODUS",
                        "options": ["Influx", "Home-coming", "Return", "Restoration"],
                        "answer": "Influx",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 5,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "RELINQUISH",
                        "options": ["Abdicate", "Renounce", "Possess", "Deny"],
                        "answer": "Possess",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 6,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "EXPAND",
                        "options": ["Convert", "Condense", "Congest", "Conclude"],
                        "answer": "Condense",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 7,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "MORTAL",
                        "options": ["Divine", "Immortal", "Spiritual", "Eternal"],
                        "answer": "Immortal",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 8,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "QUIESCENT",
                        "options": ["Active", "Dormant", "Weak", "Unconcerned"],
                        "answer": "Active",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 9,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "OBEYING",
                        "options": ["Ordering", "Following", "Refusing", "Contradicting"],
                        "answer": "Ordering",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 10,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "FRAUDULENT",
                        "options": ["Candid", "Direct", "Forthright", "Genuine"],
                        "answer": "Genuine",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 11,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "FLAGITIOUS",
                        "options": ["Innocent", "Vapid", "Ignorant", "Frivolous"],
                        "answer": "Innocent",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 12,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "BELITTLE",
                        "options": ["Criticize", "Flatter", "Exaggerate", "Adore"],
                        "answer": "Exaggerate",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 13,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "STARTLED",
                        "options": ["Amused", "Relaxed", "Endless", "Astonished"],
                        "answer": "Relaxed",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 14,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "BUSY",
                        "options": ["Occupied", "Engrossed", "Relaxed", "Engaged"],
                        "answer": "Relaxed",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 15,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "FRESH",
                        "options": ["Faulty", "Sluggish", "Disgraceful", "Stale"],
                        "answer": "Stale",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 16,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "CULPABLE",
                        "options": ["Defendable", "Blameless", "Careless", "Irresponsible"],
                        "answer": "Blameless",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 17,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "EVASIVE",
                        "options": ["Free", "Honest", "Liberal", "Frank"],
                        "answer": "Honest",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 18,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "GREGARIOUS",
                        "options": ["Antisocial", "Glorious", "Horrendous", "Similar"],
                        "answer": "Antisocial",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 19,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "AWARE",
                        "options": ["Uncertain", "Ignorant", "Sure", "Doubtful"],
                        "answer": "Ignorant",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 20,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "HIRSUTE",
                        "options": ["Scaly", "Bald", "Erudite", "Quiet"],
                        "answer": "Bald",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 21,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "SHRINK",
                        "options": ["Contract", "Spoil", "Expand", "Stretch"],
                        "answer": "Expand",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 22,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "COMMON",
                        "options": ["Rare", "Small", "Petty", "Poor"],
                        "answer": "Rare",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 23,
                        "word": "COMFORT",
                        "options": ["Uncomfort", "Miscomfort", "Discomfort", "None Of These"],
                        "answer": "Discomfort",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 24,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "DEAR",
                        "options": ["Priceless", "Free", "Worthless", "Cheap"],
                        "answer": "Cheap",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 25,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "ARROGANT",
                        "options": ["Humble", "Cowardly", "Egotistic", "Gentlemanly"],
                        "answer": "Humble",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 26,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "VICTORIOUS",
                        "options": ["Defeated", "Annexed", "Destroyed", "Vanquished"],
                        "answer": "Defeated",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 27,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "GRACEFUL",
                        "options": ["Rough", "Expert", "Miserable", "Awkward"],
                        "answer": "Awkward",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 28,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "NADIR",
                        "options": ["Modernity", "Zenith", "Liberty", "Progress"],
                        "answer": "Zenith",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 29,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "EXTRAVAGANCE",
                        "options": ["Luxury", "Poverty", "Economical", "Cheapness"],
                        "answer": "Economical",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 30,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "PERTINENT",
                        "options": ["Irrational", "Irregular", "Insistent", "Irrelevant"],
                        "answer": "Irrelevant",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 31,
                        "word": "OBSCURE",
                        "options": ["Implicit", "Obnoxious", "Explicit", "Pedantic"],
                        "answer": "Explicit",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 32,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "URBANE",
                        "options": ["Illiterate", "Backward", "Discourteous", "Orthodox"],
                        "answer": "Discourteous",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 33,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "VANITY",
                        "options": ["Pride", "Humility", "Conceit", "Ostentatious"],
                        "answer": "Humility",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 34,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "RARELY",
                        "options": ["Hardly", "Definitely", "Frequently", "Periodically"],
                        "answer": "Frequently",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 35,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "MALICIOUS",
                        "options": ["Kind", "Boastful", "Generous", "Indifferent"],
                        "answer": "Kind",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 36,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "EPILOGUE",
                        "options": ["Dialogue", "Prelude", "Post script", "Epigram"],
                        "answer": "Prelude",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 37,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "CAPACIOUS",
                        "options": ["Limited", "Caring", "Foolish", "Changeable"],
                        "answer": "Limited",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 38,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "CONDENSE",
                        "options": ["Expand", "Distribute", "Interpret", "Lengthen"],
                        "answer": "Expand",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 39,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "ADAPTABLE",
                        "options": ["Adoptable", "Flexible", "Yielding", "Rigid"],
                        "answer": "Rigid",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 40,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "SACROSANCT",
                        "options": ["Irreligious", "Unethical", "Irreverent", "Unholy"],
                        "answer": "Unholy",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 41,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "INDISCREET",
                        "options": ["Reliable", "Honest", "Prudent", "Stupid"],
                        "answer": "Prudent",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 42,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "FAMILIAR",
                        "options": ["Unpleasant", "Dangerous", "Friendly", "Strange"],
                        "answer": "Strange",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 43,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "TANGIBLE",
                        "options": ["Ethereal", "Concrete", "Actual", "Solid"],
                        "answer": "Ethereal",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 44,
                        "word": "LOVE",
                        "options": ["Villainy", "Hatred", "Compulsion", "Force"],
                        "answer": "Hatred",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 45,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "FAMOUS",
                        "options": ["Disgraced", "Unknown", "Evil", "Popular"],
                        "answer": "Unknown",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 46,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "ABSOLUTE",
                        "options": ["Deficient", "Faulty", "Limited", "Scarce"],
                        "answer": "Limited",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 47,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "FRUGAL",
                        "options": ["Copious", "Extravagant", "Generous", "Ostentatious"],
                        "answer": "Extravagant",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 48,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "INSIPID",
                        "options": ["Tasty", "Stupid", "Discreet", "Feast"],
                        "answer": "Tasty",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 49,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "ABLE",
                        "options": ["Disable", "Inable", "Unable", "Misable"],
                        "answer": "Unable",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 50,
                        "question": "In the following question choose the word which is the exact OPPOSITE of the given words.",
                        "word": "HOSTILITY",
                        "options": ["Courtesy", "Hospitality", "Relationship", "Friendliness"],
                        "answer": "Friendliness",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 51,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "CORPULENT",
                        "options": ["Lean", "Gaunt", "Emaciated", "Obese"],
                        "answer": "Obese",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 52,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "BRIEF",
                        "options": ["Limited", "Small", "Little", "Short"],
                        "answer": "Short",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 53,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "EMBEZZLE",
                        "options": ["Misappropriate", "Balance", "Remunerate", "Clear"],
                        "answer": "Misappropriate",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 54,
                        "word": "VENT",
                        "options": ["Opening", "Stodge", "End", "Past tense of go"],
                        "answer": "Opening",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 55,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "AUGUST",
                        "options": ["Common", "Ridiculous", "Dignified", "Petty"],
                        "answer": "Dignified",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 56,
                        "word": "CANNY",
                        "options": ["Obstinate", "Handsome", "Clever", "Stout"],
                        "answer": "Clever",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 57,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "ALERT",
                        "options": ["Energetic", "Observant", "Intelligent", "Watchful"],
                        "answer": "Watchful",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 58,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "WARRIOR",
                        "options": ["Soldier", "Sailor", "Pirate", "Spy"],
                        "answer": "Soldier",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 59,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "DISTANT",
                        "options": ["Far", "Removed", "Reserved", "Separate"],
                        "answer": "Far",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 60,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "ADVERSITY",
                        "options": ["Failure", "Helplessness", "Misfortune", "Crisis"],
                        "answer": "Misfortune",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 61,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "FAKE",
                        "options": ["Original", "Imitation", "Trustworthy", "Loyal"],
                        "answer": "Imitation",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 62,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "INDICT",
                        "options": ["Condemn", "Reprimand", "Accuse", "Allege"],
                        "answer": "Accuse",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 63,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "STRINGENT",
                        "options": ["Dry", "Strained", "Rigorous", "Shrill"],
                        "answer": "Rigorous",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 64,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "LAMENT",
                        "options": ["Complain", "Comment", "Condone", "Console"],
                        "answer": "Complain",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 65,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "HESITATED",
                        "options": ["Stopped", "Paused", "Slowed", "Postponed"],
                        "answer": "Paused",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 66,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "RESCUE",
                        "options": ["Command", "Help", "Defence", "Safety"],
                        "answer": "Help",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 67,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "ATTEMPT",
                        "options": ["Serve", "Explore", "Try", "Explain"],
                        "answer": "Try",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 68,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "FORAY",
                        "options": ["Maraud", "Contest", "Ranger", "Intuition"],
                        "answer": "Maraud",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 69,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "RECKLESS",
                        "options": ["Courageous", "Rash", "Bold", "Daring"],
                        "answer": "Rash",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 70,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "CONSEQUENCES",
                        "options": ["Results", "Conclusions", "Difficulties", "Applications"],
                        "answer": "Results",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 71,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "IMPROVEMENT",
                        "options": ["Advancement", "Betterment", "Promotion", "Preference"],
                        "answer": "Betterment",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 72,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "INEBRIATE",
                        "options": ["Dreamy", "Stupefied", "Unsteady", "Drunken"],
                        "answer": "Drunken",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 73,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "STERILE",
                        "options": ["Barren", "Arid", "Childless", "Dry"],
                        "answer": "Barren",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 74,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "ABJECT",
                        "options": ["Challenge", "Miserable", "Deny", "Disobey"],
                        "answer": "Miserable",
                        "s_id": 1
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 75,
                        "question": "In the following the question choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word.",
                        "word": "MOVING",
                        "options": ["Taking", "Toying", "Shifting", "Turning"],
                        "answer": "Shifting",
                        "s_id": 1
                    }
                ]
            },
            











            {
                "section": "English Ability",
                "subsection": "Error detection",
                "questions": [
                    {
                        "id": 1,
                        "question": "We discussed about the problem so thoroughly on the eve of the examination that I found it very easy to work it out.",
                        "options": [
                            "We discussed about the problem so thoroughly",
                            "on the eve of the examination",
                            "that I found it very easy to work it out",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "We discussed about the problem so thoroughly",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 2,
                        "question": "An Indian ship laden with merchandise got drowned in the Pacific Ocean.",
                        "options": [
                            "An Indian ship",
                            "laden with merchandise",
                            "got drowned in the Pacific Ocean.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "got drowned in the Pacific Ocean.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 3,
                        "question": "I could not put up in a hotel because the boarding and lodging charges were exorbitant.",
                        "options": [
                            "I could not put up in a hotel",
                            "because the boarding and lodging charges",
                            "were exorbitant.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "I could not put up in a hotel",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 4,
                        "question": "The Indian radio which was previously controlled by the British rulers is free now from the narrow vested interests.",
                        "options": [
                            "The Indian radio",
                            "which was previously controlled by the British rulers",
                            "is free now from the narrow vested interests.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "is free now from the narrow vested interests",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 5,
                        "question": "If I had known this yesterday I will have helped him.",
                        "options": [
                            "If I had known",
                            "this yesterday",
                            "I will have helped him.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "I will have helped him.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 6,
                        "question": "A lot of travel delay is caused due to the inefficiency and lack of good management on behalf of the railways.",
                        "options": [
                            "A lot of travel delay is caused",
                            "due to the inefficiency and lack of good management",
                            "on behalf of the railways.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "on behalf of the railways.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 7,
                        "question": "One of the members expressed doubt if the Minister was an atheist.",
                        "options": [
                            "One of the members",
                            "expressed doubt if",
                            "the Minister was an atheist.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "expressed doubt if",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 8,
                        "question": "I have got my M.Sc. degree in 1988.",
                        "options": [
                            "I have got",
                            "my M.Sc. degree",
                            "in 1988.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "I have got",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 9,
                        "question": "Having received your letter this morning, we are writing to thank you for the same.",
                        "options": [
                            "Having received your letter",
                            "this morning, we are writing",
                            "to thank you for the same.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "No error.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 10,
                        "question": "If you lend him a book he will lend it to someone else and never you will get it back.",
                        "options": [
                            "If you lend him a book",
                            "he will lend it to someone else",
                            "and never you will get it back.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "and never you will get it back.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 11,
                        "question": "According to the Bible, it is meek and humble who shall inherit the earth.",
                        "options": [
                            "According to the Bible",
                            "it is meek and humble",
                            "who shall inherit the earth.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "it is meek and humble",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 12,
                        "question": "Do the roses in your garden smell more sweetly than those in ours?",
                        "options": [
                            "Do the roses in your garden smell",
                            "more sweetly",
                            "than those in ours?",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "more sweetly",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 13,
                        "question": "Block of Residential flats are coming up near our house.",
                        "options": [
                            "Block of Residential flats",
                            "are coming up",
                            "near our house.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "Block of Residential flats",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 14,
                        "question": "You can get all the information that you want in this book.",
                        "options": [
                            "You can get",
                            "all the information that you want",
                            "in this book.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "all the information that you want",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 15,
                        "question": "The students were awaiting for the arrival of the chief guest.",
                        "options": [
                            "The students were",
                            "awaiting for",
                            "the arrival of the chief guest.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "awaiting for",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 16,
                        "question": "Sixty miles are a good distance.",
                        "options": [
                            "Sixty miles",
                            "are",
                            "a good distance.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "are",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 17,
                        "question": "They have been very close friends until they quarrelled.",
                        "options": [
                            "They have been",
                            "very close friends",
                            "until they quarrelled.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "They have been",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 18,
                        "question": "When the dentist came in my tooth was stopped aching out of fear that I might lose my tooth.",
                        "options": [
                            "When the dentist came in",
                            "my tooth was stopped aching",
                            "out of fear that I might lose my tooth.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "my tooth was stopped aching",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 19,
                        "question": "It is the duty of every citizen to do his utmost to defend the hardly-won freedom of the country.",
                        "options": [
                            "It is the duty of every citizen to do his utmost",
                            "to defend the hardly-won",
                            "freedom of the country.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "to defend the hardly-won",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 20,
                        "question": "No sooner did I open the door when the rain, heavy and stormy, rushed in making us shiver from head to foot.",
                        "options": [
                            "No sooner did I open the door",
                            "when the rain, heavy and stormy, rushed in",
                            "making us shiver from head to foot.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "when the rain, heavy and stormy, rushed in",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 21,
                        "question": "If a man diligently seeks to come into the contact with the best that has been thought and said in this world he will become simple and unselfish.",
                        "options": [
                            "If a man diligently seeks to come into the contact",
                            "with the best that has been thought and said in this world",
                            "he will become simple and unselfish.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "If a man diligently seeks to come into the contact",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 22,
                        "question": "You must remember me to post this letter.",
                        "options": [
                            "You must",
                            "remember me",
                            "to post this letter.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "remember me",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 23,
                        "question": "I shall certainly write you when I shall reach New Delhi.",
                        "options": [
                            "I shall certainly",
                            "write you",
                            "when I shall reach New Delhi.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "when I shall reach New Delhi.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 24,
                        "question": "On the busy Ring Road we witnessed a collusion between a truck and an auto.",
                        "options": [
                            "On the busy Ring Road",
                            "we witnessed a collusion",
                            "between a truck and an auto.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "we witnessed a collusion",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 25,
                        "question": "Mr. Praful Patel is not attending his office for the last month.",
                        "options": [
                            "Mr. Praful Patel",
                            "is not attending his office",
                            "for the last month.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "is not attending his office",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 26,
                        "question": "He couldn't but help shedding tears at the plight of the villagers rendered homeless by a devastating cyclone.",
                        "options": [
                            "He couldn't but help",
                            "shedding tears at the plight of the villagers",
                            "rendered homeless by a devastating cyclone.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "He couldn't but help",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 27,
                        "question": "He will certainly help you if you will ask him in a pleasant manner.",
                        "options": [
                            "He will certainly help you",
                            "if you will ask him",
                            "in a pleasant manner.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "if you will ask him",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 28,
                        "question": "The brand proposition now therefore had to be that Keokarpin Antiseptic Cream is more effective because it penetrates deep down (being light and non-sticky) and works from within (because of its ayurvedic ingredients) to keep skin blemish free and helps cope with cuts nicks, burns and nappy rash.",
                        "options": [
                            "The brand proposition now therefore had to be that Keokarpin Antiseptic Cream is more effective",
                            "because it penetrates deep down (being light and non-sticky) and works from within",
                            "(because of its ayurvedic ingredients) to keep skin blemish free and helps cope with cuts nicks, burns and nappy rash.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "The brand proposition now therefore had to be that Keokarpin Antiseptic Cream is more effective",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 29,
                        "question": "Will you please buy some jaggery for me if you go to the market?",
                        "options": [
                            "Will you please buy",
                            "some jaggery for me",
                            "if you go to the market?",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "No error.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 30,
                        "question": "Most of the members at the meeting felt that the group appointed for investigating the case were not competent to do the job efficiently.",
                        "options": [
                            "Most of the members at the meeting felt",
                            "that the group appointed for investigating the case",
                            "were not competent to do the job efficiently.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "were not competent to do the job efficiently.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 31,
                        "question": "In these days of inflation, a ten rupee's note will not buy you even an ordinary meal.",
                        "options": [
                            "In these days of inflation,",
                            "a ten rupee's note will not buy you",
                            "even an ordinary meal.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "a ten rupee's note will not buy you",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 32,
                        "question": "He persisted to do it in spite of my advice.",
                        "options": [
                            "He persisted",
                            "to do it",
                            "in spite of my advice",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "to do it",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 33,
                        "question": "The long-awaited moment at last came, and we set out for the station as merry a band of children as I have ever seen before or since.",
                        "options": [
                            "The long-awaited moment at last came,",
                            "and we set out for the station",
                            "as merry a band of children as I have ever seen before or since.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "as merry a band of children as I have ever seen before or since.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 34,
                        "question": "Our conception of what should a science of mental life be has changed considerably since James' time.",
                        "options": [
                            "Our conception of",
                            "what should a science of mental life be",
                            "has changed considerably since James' time.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "what should a science of mental life be",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 35,
                        "question": "He is not coming tomorrow as he is having a pain in the chest and has to see a doctor.",
                        "options": [
                            "He is not coming tomorrow",
                            "as he is having a pain in the chest",
                            "and has to see a doctor.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "and has to see a doctor.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
            
                    {
                        "id": 36,
                        "question": "Many times the news has been published in the papers that the end of the world will be certain if a nuclear war breaks out.",
                        "options": [
                            "Many times the news has been published",
                            "in the papers that the end of the world will be certain",
                            "if a nuclear war breaks out.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "No error.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 37,
                        "question": "The reason Ram is absent from his duty is because he is unwell.",
                        "options": [
                            "The reason Ram",
                            "is absent from his duty",
                            "is because he is unwell.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "The reason Ram",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 38,
                        "question": "Azharuddin is one of the finest batsmen that India have produced over the decades.",
                        "options": [
                            "Azharuddin is one of the finest batsmen",
                            "that India have produced",
                            "over the decades.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "that India have produced",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 39,
                        "question": "The thief broke in the house at the dead of night.",
                        "options": [
                            "The thief broke in the",
                            "house at the",
                            "dead of night.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "The thief broke in the",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 40,
                        "question": "May I know who you want to see please.",
                        "options": [
                            "May I",
                            "know who you want",
                            "to see please.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "know who you want",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 41,
                        "question": "He said that he will mind if I refused his offer.",
                        "options": [
                            "He said that he",
                            "will mind if",
                            "I refused his offer.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "will mind if",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 42,
                        "question": "Arun's parents died when he was young and he looked after his aunt who had no children.",
                        "options": [
                            "Arun's parents died when he was young and",
                            "he looked after his aunt",
                            "who had no children.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "he looked after his aunt",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 43,
                        "question": "Though child marriage has been banned, the custom still prevailed among some groups in India.",
                        "options": [
                            "Though child marriage",
                            "has been banned.",
                            "the custom still prevailed among some groups in India.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "the custom still prevailed among some groups in India.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 44,
                        "question": "My papa is in bad mood today.",
                        "options": [
                            "My papa is",
                            "in bad mood",
                            "today.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "in bad mood",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 45,
                        "question": "The warden forbade the student from leaving the hostel.",
                        "options": [
                            "The warden",
                            "forbade the student",
                            "from leaving the hostel.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "No error.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 46,
                        "question": "In spite of several reminders, he did not so far send any reply to me, letters.",
                        "options": [
                            "In spite of several reminders,",
                            "he did not so far send",
                            "any reply to me, letters.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "he did not so far send",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 47,
                        "question": "As much as I admire him for his sterling qualities, I cannot excuse him for being unfair to his friends.",
                        "options": [
                            "As much as I admire him for his sterling qualities.",
                            "I cannot excuse him for",
                            "being unfair to his friends.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "As much as I admire him for his sterling qualities.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 48,
                        "question": "Please try to understand that the dispute on this issue is between my brother and myself, and concerns nobody else.",
                        "options": [
                            "Please try to understand",
                            "that the dispute on this issue is between my brother and myself,",
                            "and concerns nobody else.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "that the dispute on this issue is between my brother and myself,",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 49,
                        "question": "All the furnitures have been sent to the new house located in a village.",
                        "options": [
                            "All the furnitures have been",
                            "sent to the new house",
                            "located in a village.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "All the furnitures have been",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 50,
                        "question": "It does not matter how you do it; what I want is that you should finish the work within a month.",
                        "options": [
                            "It does not matter how you do it;",
                            "what I want is that",
                            "you should finish the work within a month.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "what I want is that",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 51,
                        "question": "Though senior in age, his father is junior than my father in service.",
                        "options": [
                            "Though senior in age,",
                            "his father is junior than",
                            "my father in service.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "his father is junior than",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 52,
                        "question": "While walking slowly in the park on a quiet summer afternoon a mad dog suddenly attacked him from behind.",
                        "options": [
                            "While walking slowly in the park",
                            "on a quiet summer afternoon",
                            "a mad dog suddenly attacked him from behind.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "While walking slowly in the park",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 53,
                        "question": "Everyone visiting the house asked the young girl how could she kill the wolf single handed and without a weapon.",
                        "options": [
                            "Everyone visiting the house asked the young girl",
                            "how could she kill the wolf",
                            "single handed and without a weapon.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "how could she kill the wolf",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 54,
                        "question": "Many health-conscious people prefer margarine than butter.",
                        "options": [
                            "Many health-conscious people",
                            "prefer margarine",
                            "than butter.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "than butter.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 55,
                        "question": "The retiring principal asked his old pupils to take the interest in the school after he has retired.",
                        "options": [
                            "The retiring principal asked his old pupils",
                            "to take the interest in the school",
                            "after he has retired.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "to take the interest in the school",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 56,
                        "question": "At present juncture however, the supercomputer would be a costly toy.",
                        "options": [
                            "At present juncture",
                            "however, the supercomputer",
                            "would be a costly toy.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "At present juncture",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 57,
                        "question": "The crew were on board, and they soon busied themselves in preparing to meet the storm.",
                        "options": [
                            "The crew were on board,",
                            "and they soon busied themselves",
                            "in preparing to meet the storm.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "in preparing to meet the storm.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 58,
                        "question": "Troy was taken by Greeks this formed the basis of a story which has become famous.",
                        "options": [
                            "Troy was taken by Greeks",
                            "this formed the basis of a story",
                            "which has become famous.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "Troy was taken by Greeks",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 59,
                        "question": "I am much pleased to know that you have topped the list.",
                        "options": [
                            "I am much pleased",
                            "to know that",
                            "you have topped the list.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "I am much pleased",
                        "s_id": 2
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 60,
                        "question": "He has not been attending English classes since one month.",
                        "options": [
                            "He has not been attending",
                            "English classes",
                            "since one month.",
                            "No error."
                        ],
                        "answer": "since one month.",
                        "s_id": 2
                    }
                ]
            },
                    













            {
                "section": "English Ability",
                "subsection": "Para Jumbles",
                "questions": [
                    {
                        "id": 1,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nWhen he\nP: did not know\nQ: he was nervous and\nR: heard the hue and cry at midnight\nS: what to do",
                        "options": ["RQPS", "QSPR", "SQPR", "PQRS"],
                        "answer": "RQPS",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 2,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nIt has been established that\nP: Einstein was\nQ: although a great scientist\nR: weak in arithmetic\nS: right from his school days",
                        "options": ["SRPQ", "QPRS", "QPSR", "RQPS"],
                        "answer": "QPRS",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 3,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nThen\nP: it struck me\nQ: of course\nR: suitable it was\nS: how eminently",
                        "options": ["SPQR", "QSRP", "PSRQ", "QPSR"],
                        "answer": "PSRQ",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 4,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nI read an advertisement that said\nP: posh, air-conditioned\nQ: gentleman of taste\nR: are available for\nS: fully furnished rooms",
                        "options": ["PQRS", "PSRQ", "PSQR", "SRPQ"],
                        "answer": "PSRQ",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 5,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nSince the beginning of history\nP: have managed to catch\nQ: the Eskimos and Red Indians\nR: by a very difficulty method\nS: a few specimens of this aquatic animal",
                        "options": ["QRPS", "SQPR", "SQRP", "QPSR"],
                        "answer": "QPSR",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 6,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nA French woman\nP: committed suicide\nQ: where she had put up\nR: who had come to Calcutta\nS: by jumping from the first floor balcony of the hotel",
                        "options": ["PRQS", "QSRP", "RPSQ", "SRQP"],
                        "answer": "RPSQ",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 7,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nThe national unity of a free people\nP: to make it impracticable\nQ: for there to be an arbitrary administration\nR: depends upon a sufficiently even balance of political power\nS: against a revolutionary opposition that is irreconcilably opposed to it",
                        "options": ["QRPS", "QRSP", "RPQS", "RSPQ"],
                        "answer": "RSPQ",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 8,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nThe grocer\nP: did not listen to the protests of customer\nQ: who was in the habit of weighing less\nR: whom he had cheated\nS: with great audacity",
                        "options": ["PRSQ", "QSPR", "QPRS", "PQSR"],
                        "answer": "QPRS",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 9,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nThey felt safer\nP: to watch the mountain\nQ: of more than five miles\nR: as they settled down\nS: from a distance",
                        "options": ["RPSQ", "RSQP", "PQSR", "PRSQ"],
                        "answer": "RPSQ",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 10,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nPeople\nP: at his dispensary\nQ: went to him\nR: of all professions\nS: for medicine and treatment",
                        "options": ["QPRS", "RPQS", "RQSP", "QRPS"],
                        "answer": "RQSP",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 11,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nIf you need help\nP: promptly and politely\nQ: ask for attendants\nR: to help our customers\nS: who have instructions",
                        "options": ["SQPR", "QPSR", "QSRP", "SQRP"],
                        "answer": "QSRP",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 12,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nIt is easier\nP: to venture into space\nQ: for men\nR: beneath their feet\nS: than to explore",
                        "options": ["QRPS", "QPSR", "PSRQ", "PQSR"],
                        "answer": "QPSR",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 13,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nIt was to be\nP: before their school examination\nQ: which was due to start\nR: the last expedition\nS: in a month's",
                        "options": ["SRQP", "RQSP", "RPQS", "SPRQ"],
                        "answer": "RPQS",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 14,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nThis time\nP: exactly what he had been told\nQ: the young man did\nR: beyond his dreams\nS: and the plan succeeded",
                        "options": ["QPRS", "QPSR", "PQSR", "QSRP"],
                        "answer": "QPSR",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 15,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nIn the darkness\nP: the long, narrow beard\nQ: was clearly visible with\nR: the tall stooping figure of the doctor\nS: and the aquiline nose",
                        "options": ["RQPS", "PSQR", "RSQP", "QPRS"],
                        "answer": "RQPS",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 16,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nWe have to\nP: as we see it\nQ: speak the truth\nR: there is falsehood and weakness\nS: even if all around us",
                        "options": ["RQSP", "QRPS", "RSQP", "QPSR"],
                        "answer": "QPSR",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 17,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nWhen it began to rain suddenly on the first of January\nP: to celebrate the new year\nQ: we ran for shelter\nR: to the neighbouring house\nS: where many people had gathered",
                        "options": ["QRPS", "PSQR", "PRSQ", "QRSP"],
                        "answer": "QRSP",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 18,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nHe told us that\nP: and enjoyed it immensely\nQ: in a prose translation\nR: he had read Milton\nS: which he had borrowed from his teacher",
                        "options": ["RSQP", "QRPS", "RQSP", "RQPS"],
                        "answer": "RQSP",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 19,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nHe knew that\nP: and then to save himself\nQ: was to save all the lives\nR: entrusted to his care\nS: the duty of a captain",
                        "options": ["PQRS", "SQRP", "SPRQ", "QSRP"],
                        "answer": "SQRP",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 20,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nIt is not, therefore\nP: that I pay a tribute\nQ: to conductors as a class\nR: with any feeling of unfriendliness\nS: to a particular member of that class",
                        "options": ["PQRS", "RQPS", "RSPQ", "PSRQ"],
                        "answer": "RSPQ",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 21,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nOf many artists\nP: those who impressed me the most\nQ: I was a child\nR: but those with unique personalities off stage\nS: were not always the successful ones",
                        "options": ["SRQP", "QRSP", "RSPQ", "QPSR"],
                        "answer": "QPSR",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 22,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nAs a disease\nP: and breaks up marriages\nQ: accidents and suicides\nR: alcoholism leads to\nS: affecting all ages",
                        "options": ["SRPQ", "RPSQ", "SRQP", "RQPS"],
                        "answer": "SRQP",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 23,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nIt is easy to excuse\nP: but it is hard\nQ: in a boy of fourteen\nR: the mischief of early childhood\nS: to tolerate even unavoidable faults",
                        "options": ["RPQS", "QRSP", "QRPS", "RPSQ"],
                        "answer": "RPSQ",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 24,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nThe majestic mahogany table\nP: belongs to an old prince\nQ: which has one leg missing\nR: who is no impoverished\nS: but not without some pride",
                        "options": ["PQSR", "QRSP", "PRSQ", "QPRS"],
                        "answer": "QPRS",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 25,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nEducation is\nP: of the proper sense of responsibilities\nQ: the first need\nR: in a citizen\nS: for the development",
                        "options": ["SQPR", "QSRP", "QSPR", "PQRS"],
                        "answer": "QSPR",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 26,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nIt would\nP: appear from his statement\nQ: about the policy of management\nR: in dealing with the strike\nS: that he was quite in the dark",
                        "options": ["RPSQ", "PSQR", "RQPS", "PRQS"],
                        "answer": "PSQR",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 27,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nHe was so kind and generous that\nP: he not only\nQ: made others do so\nR: but also\nS: helped them himself",
                        "options": ["PSRQ", "SPQR", "PRSQ", "QPRS"],
                        "answer": "PSRQ",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 28,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nWe went\nP: along the railway line\nQ: and had a right to\nR: where other people not allowed to go\nS: but daddy belonged to the railway",
                        "options": ["RPQS", "PRSQ", "RSQP", "PRQS"],
                        "answer": "PRSQ",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 29,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nThere was\nP: needed for it everyday life\nQ: a time when each family\nR: for itself most of the things it\nS: actually produced",
                        "options": ["QRSP", "RQPS", "RSPQ", "QSRP"],
                        "answer": "QSRP",
                        "s_id": 3
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 30,
                        "question": "Rearrange these parts to produce the correct sentence:\nLittle\nP: that he had been let down\nQ: stood by all these years\nR: did he realise\nS: by a colleague whom he had",
                        "options": ["RPSQ", "RSQP", "QSRP", "QSPR"],
                        "answer": "RPSQ",
                        "s_id": 3
                    }
                ]
            },
            










            {
                "section": "English Ability",
                "subsection": "Sentence Improvement",
                "questions": [
                    {
                        "id": 1,
                        "question": "The workers are hell bent at getting what is due to them.",
                        "options": [
                            "hell bent on getting",
                            "hell bent for getting",
                            "hell bent upon getting",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "hell bent upon getting",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 2,
                        "question": "When it was feared that the serfs might go too far and gain their freedom from serfdom, the protestant leaders joined the princes at crushing them.",
                        "options": [
                            "into crushing",
                            "in crushing",
                            "without crushing",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "in crushing",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 3,
                        "question": "If the room had been brighter, I would have been able to read for a while before bed time.",
                        "options": [
                            "If the room was brighter",
                            "If the room are brighter",
                            "Had the room been brighter",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "Had the room been brighter",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 4,
                        "question": "The record for the biggest tiger hunt has not been met since 1911 when Lord Hardinge, then Viceroy of India, shot a tiger than measured 11 feet and 6 inches.",
                        "options": [
                            "improved",
                            "broken",
                            "bettered",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "broken",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 5,
                        "question": "his powerful desire brought about his downfall.",
                        "options": [
                            "His intense desire",
                            "His desire for power",
                            "His fatal desire",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "His desire for power",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 6,
                        "question": "Will you kindly open the knot?",
                        "options": [
                            "untie",
                            "break",
                            "loose",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "untie",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 7,
                        "question": "He sent a word to me that he would be coming late.",
                        "options": [
                            "sent word",
                            "had sent a word",
                            "sent words",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "sent word",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 8,
                        "question": "John had told me that he hasn't done it yet.",
                        "options": [
                            "told",
                            "tells",
                            "was telling",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "tells",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 9,
                        "question": "If he had time he will call you.",
                        "options": [
                            "would have",
                            "would have had",
                            "has",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "has",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 10,
                        "question": "Will you lend me few rupees in this hour of need?",
                        "options": [
                            "lend me any rupees",
                            "borrow me a few rupees",
                            "lend me a few rupees",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "lend me a few rupees",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 11,
                        "question": "During his long discourse, he did not touch that point.",
                        "options": [
                            "touch upon",
                            "touch on",
                            "touch of",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "touch on",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 12,
                        "question": "He found a wooden broken chair in the room.",
                        "options": [
                            "wooden and broken chair",
                            "broken wooden chair",
                            "broken and wooden chair",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "broken wooden chair",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 13,
                        "question": "He could not look anything in the dark room.",
                        "options": [
                            "look at",
                            "see",
                            "see through",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "see",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 14,
                        "question": "The greatest thing in style is to have a use of metaphor.",
                        "options": [
                            "knowledge",
                            "command",
                            "need",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "The greatest thing in style is to have a use of metaphor.",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 15,
                        "question": "While crossing the highway a five year old child was knocked out by a passing car.",
                        "options": [
                            "away",
                            "up",
                            "down",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "down",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 16,
                        "question": "Hoping not to be disturbed, I sat down in my easy chair to read the book. I won as a prize.",
                        "options": [
                            "I had won as a prize",
                            "I have won as prize",
                            "I had to win as a prize",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "I had won as a prize",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 17,
                        "question": "More than one person was killed in accident.",
                        "options": [
                            "were killed",
                            "are killed",
                            "have been killed",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "No improvement",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 18,
                        "question": "No one could explain how a calm and balanced person like him could penetrate such a mindless act on his friends.",
                        "options": [
                            "perpetuate",
                            "perpetrate",
                            "precipitate",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "perpetrate",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 19,
                        "question": "Five years ago today, I am sitting in a small Japanese car, driving across Poland towards Berlin.",
                        "options": [
                            "was sitting",
                            "sat",
                            "have been sitting",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "was sitting",
                        "s_id": 4
                    },
                    {
                        "id": 20,
                        "question": "I took the cycle which he bought yesterday.",
                        "options": [
                            "that he bought yesterday",
                            "that which he had bought yesterday",
                            "that he had bought yesterday",
                            "No improvement"
                        ],
                        "answer": "that he had bought yesterday",
                        "s_id": 4
                    }
                ]
            }            
    ]
}    